那些我们总是吵的事 这些烂事...
What it's always about. This, this...and this.
她差不多一天后会回来
She'll be back in a day or so.
十分狼狈
In a right mess
"我很抱歉 Lee 请你原谅我 Lee"
"I'm so sorry, Lee. Please forgive me, Lee."
对 是啊 直到她下次再这样
Yeah, right. Till the next time.
只是 她从来没离开过那么久
Only, she's never stayed away this long before.
我们吵架的时候她就睡在这里
She sleeps in here when we've had a ruck
这几天就是这样
which is like always these days.
你是涂料用完了吗?
Did you run out of paint?
我想让她振奋起来
I was trying to cheer her up a bit.
她却发疯 咆哮着说
She went mental, ranting on about how
她只配住铁屋子
she didn't deserve nothing apart from a hard room.
然后她就走了
And then she just buggered off.
我只是想让她开心
I just want her to be happy.
我们需要张照片
We'll need a photo.
是个恶作剧 都是胡闹
It was mischief. A prank.
但是那些文件让这事看起来成了某种邪恶的仪式
But the papers made out it was some sort of Satanic ritual.
而事实是
The truth is,
从没有人把Jenny和我教育得懂得是非曲直
Jenny and I were never taught the difference between right and wrong.
直到你们遇到Helen Jenkins?
Until you met Helen Jenkins?
她当然觉得她懂道理 并且知道怎么教我们
She certainly thought she knew the difference and how to teach us.
为什么你之前没提到这事?
Why didn't you mention this before?
看起来无关啊
Didn't seem relevant.
那是很久以前的事了 我们那时都还是孩子
It was such a long time ago and we were kids.
孤儿院关门的时候 我想离它尽可能的远
When the home closed, I wanted to get as far away from it as possible.
我知道我一直不好
I knew I'd been bad
但似乎那是个重新开始的理想时刻
but it seemed like an ideal moment to make a new start.
问题是 Jenny做不到
Problem was, Jenny couldn't.
她跟错了人 我们就分道扬镳了
She got in with the wrong crowd and we went our separate ways.
但你们曾经很亲密?
But you were close once?
曾经
Once.
她曾是这个世界上我唯一的朋友 Mathias先生
She was the only friend I had in the world, Mr Mathias.
Helen很为Catrin骄傲
她觉得她一定会有所成就
她没有Jenny成功
这个嘛...Jenny遇到Helen的时候已经是一缕迷失的灵魂了
Jenny有没有向你倾诉过?
我鼓励所有的孩子来和我交流
但他们几乎不会说真话
我需要你上周日穿的鞋子
好的 当然
我现在去拿给你
你自便 喝点茶
Agnes?
Maybury!
我得找人谈谈
I need to talk to someone.
- Mathias - 你最好尽快赶回来 长官
- Mathias. - You'd better get back here as soon as possible, sir.
为什么 什么事?
Why, what is it?
Jenny James刚刚来自首了
Jenny James has just turned herself in.
她说她杀了Helen Jenkins
She says she killed Helen Jenkins.
你为什么躲在那 Hywel?
Why were you hiding there, Hywel?
你是害怕吗?
Were you scared?
你逃跑是不是因为你干了什么坏事?
Were you running away because you did something you were ashamed of?
你有没有杀Helen Jenkins Hywel?
Did you kill Helen Jenkins, Hywel?
- 你怎么杀死她的? - 我打了她
- How did you kill her? - I hit her.
用什么?
With what?
一个花瓶 打破了她的脑袋
A vase. Smashed her head in.
把那个贱人的牙齿都打出来了
Knocked the bitch's teeth out.
你为什么那么做?
Why did you do that?
她不用麻醉就拔我们的牙齿 就喜欢看我们受折磨
She took out our teeth with no anaesthetic, liked seeing us suffer.
我让她体会下她自己的医术
I gave her a taste of her own medicine.
之后你干嘛了?
Then what did you do?
刺她
Stabbed her.
把她拖出前门然后放在车上
Dragged her out the front door and put her in the car.
什么车
What sort of car?
一辆红色的小车
A little red one.
然后我开到了恶魔桥
Then I drove it up to Devil's Bridge.
然后你干嘛了?
And then what did you do?
停在桥上
Stopped on the bridge.
把她拖出来 推下河
Pulled her out and shoved her into the river.
你有没有帮手?
Did you have help?
没有
No.
你自己一个人把她拖出车来
You took her out of the car
然后举过栏杆吗?
and lifted her over the parapet on your own?
是的
Yeah.
你们俩看起来都很开心
You look happy the both of you.
我很开心
I was happy.
她很开心
She was happy.
那是愉快的一天
It was a happy day.
听起来真美好
Sounds lovely.
跟我说说吧
Tell me about it.
那天是我生日
It was my birthday.
所以 我去钓鱼...
So, I went out fishing...
...然后我钓到了一条海鲈鱼 她做给我吃
..and I caught a sea bass and she cooked it for me.
Helen吗? Helen做的鱼吗?
Helen? Did Helen cook the fish?
所以因此你才星期六去那儿吗?
Is that why you went round there on Saturday?
她可以做饭给你吃?
So she could cook for you?
星期六发生什么了 Hywel?
What happened on Saturday, Hywel?
我很害怕
I was scared.
所以我才逃跑
That's why I ran away.
她有没有做什么让你生气的事?
Did she do something that made you angry?
不是我的错
It wasn't my fault.
我去那 是因为我曾经住在那
I went there, because I used to live there.
去Helen的房子?
To Helen's house?
那个酒店!
The hotel!
我们曾住在那 那曾是我们的家
We lived there once. It was our home.
我想我在那会安全
I thought I'd be safe.
但哪都不安全
But nowhere's safe.
- 他们总是唾弃我 - 谁?
- They always spit in your face. - Who does?
所有人! 他们都怪我
Everyone! They blame me.
那不是我的错!
It wasn't my fault!
Helen怪你吗 Hywel?
Did Helen blame you, Hywel?
所以你才生气吗?
Is that why you were angry?
她有没有吼你? 直接叫你的名字?
Did she shout at you? Did she call you names?
所以你就伤害她?
Is that why you hurt her?
Hywel!
HYWEL!
我没有伤害她! 我根本没碰她!
I didn't hurt her! I didn't touch her!
我没有 我没有!
I didn't. I didn't!
够了
That's enough.
他在那
He was there.
他的鞋印和小屋里的吻合 他在那
His waders match the prints in the chalet. He was there.
- 他有没有杀她? - 他肯定足够力量杀死她
- Did he kill her? - He's certainly capable of killing her.
不管他做了什么 看见什么 都深深地伤害了他
Whatever he did, whatever he saw, he's deeply traumatised by it.
- 会不会是装的? - 不 不 我认为是真的
- Could it be an act? - No, no, I think it's genuine.
DCI Mathias...?
我很抱歉
I'm sorry,
但是我的客户目前的情况不适合被询问
but my client isn't in any fit mental state to be interviewed.
我想让他在进行进一步询问前做心理评估
I'd like him psychologically assessed before further questioning.
无意冒犯 但我想你有点太着急了
With respect, I think you're being a little premature.
让我继续询问 如果他又崩溃了 那我会...
Let me continue the interview if he breaks down again, then I'll...
- 很抱歉 必须得就此打住了 - Walters女士
- I'm sorry. It has to stop now. - Ms Walters,
这是一个谋杀询问 我们首要关心的是找到凶手
this is a murder enquiry, our primary concern is, is to find the killer.
我可不可以提议我们相信
Can I suggest that we trust the judgment of
Haydn Blake医生的判断 他是我们警方评估Maybury先生
Dr Haydn Blake, our police surgeon in assessing Mr Maybury's
是否能继续的医生?
fitness to continue?
请随意使用我办公室里的电话 请
Feel free to use the phone in my office. Please.
Jenny 嗨
Jenny, hi.
你认识这张图吗?
Do you know this picture?
认识
Yeah.
她家里墙上挂着一张
She had one hanging on the wall at the home.
她在别处还有吗?
Did she have one anywhere else?
我怎么知道?
How would I know?
车后面放着一具尸体时 恶魔桥走起来挺长的
Devil's Bridge is a long way to go with a body in the back of the car.
你不担心被抓吗?
Weren't you worried about being caught?
从没想过
Never thought about it.
为什么选恶魔桥 Jenny?
Why Devil's Bridge, Jenny?
我们是坏孩子时 她就是在那接我们
It's where she took us when we'd been bad.
走到尽头...说恶魔住在那
Down the bottom... said the Devil lived there.
如果我们不忏悔
If we didn't repent
他就会取走我们的灵魂 让我们在地狱永世燃烧
he'd take our souls and we'd burn in Hell for ever.